Jennifer Martinez 1544B Schenone Court Concord, CA 94521 (206) 235-7172 Jenn.A.Martinez@outlook.com

Summary

Experienced Professional with a demonstrated history of working in the internet, healthcare, and sales industry. Currently, gaining skills in full stack web development. Long-standing skills in Statistical Data Analysis, Sales, Analytics, Communication, Assessment, Management, Training, and Organizational & Writing Skills. Gained multicultural skills, diversity and inclusion training through education at the doctoral level, while applying these skills in a professional environment with clients and within communities. Consistently collaborating, project management, rapport building, and relationship management of clients, consumers, and professionals.

Education

University of California, Berkeley Extension Full Stack Web Development 2018-Present

John F. Kennedy University

Doctorate of Clinical Psychology, PsyD Program, 2015 - 2018

Master of Arts - MA, Clinical Psychology, 2011 - 2015 Activities: Curriculum Committee Member 2014-2015

Ashford University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Psychology, 2010

Honors and Societies:

Alpha Sigma Lambda, National Honour Society, Golden Key International Honour Society

Sonoma State University

Pre-Nursing Studies, General Studies, 2001 - 2003

Experience

Lyft – Bay Area, CA

Rideshare Driver

August 2017 - Present

- Picking up/dropping off riders, while providing quality customer service
- Acting in accordance with CA driving laws, while maintaining safety at all times
- Maintaining a high success rating
- Keeping a neat and tidy vehicle
- Personal recording

California Department of Rehabilitation - Antioch, CA

Clinical Psychology Intern

July 2015 - May 2017

- Psychological assessor intern; Supervisor extern, Management
- Psychological assessment and evaluation
- Statistical data analysis and comparison
- Report writing
- Risk assessment
- Develop medical, vocational, clinical, educational, and psychological recommendations
- Provided referrals while advocating for clients
- Consistent client collaboration
- Helped organize and arrange formal interviews for incoming students, while acting as an interviewer on a panel with my current internship team
- Mentoring and supervising incoming practicum students at the site; flexibility
- Researching and scheduling community organizations to conduct outreach presentations
- Collaborating with fellow externship students and professionals within the community to create, develop, and manage a program that was strong, serving as a comprehensive didactic training experience
- Conducting and administering group and individual assessments: aptitude, intellectual functioning, neuropsychological/cognitive functioning, personality (subjective, objective, and projective), academic achievement, and other standardized assessments
- Working collaboratively with vocational and rehabilitation counselors, medical specialists, and other assessors to effectively provide services to clients assessed and evaluated for physical, psychological, and intellectual disabilities, in regard to the assessment results

Anka Behavioral Health, Inc. - Vallejo, CA

Drug and Alcohol Counselor

HOPE Solano Alcohol and Other Drugs (AOD) Services - ANKA Behavioral, Inc. July 2014 – June 2015 ADAPT Adolescent Services - ANKA Behavioral, Inc., 2015

- AOD and behavioral health counselor adult and adolescent forensic populations
- Assessment and evaluation
- Progress notes and court reporting
- Treating court-mandated clients to participate in intensive outpatient therapy for substance use and dual-diagnoses
- Treating CalWorks clients with affected employment statuses, due to their psychological symptoms and diagnoses
- Facilitating intensive individual and process group therapy sessions
- Incorporating psycho-education, focusing on mood management and relapse prevention
- Professional exposure and treatment planning, therapeutic, and risk assessment skills
- Various psychological treatment modalities
- AOD and behavioral health counselor Juvenile Population
- Conducting individual and psycho-educational group relapse prevention sessions
- Minimizing substance use and suicidal and homicidal thoughts
- Collaborating with colleagues, psychiatrists, parole officers, probation officers, assessors, drug and criminal courts, school personnel, parental guardians, and social workers and other county employees, helping to create a sound foundation, safe and healthy environment for our clients to be successfully rehabilitated

Bay Area Alliance for Youth - Pittsburg, CA

Social Worker/Facility Manager

January 2011 - December 2011

- · Peer interactions and socialization
- · Medication distribution and management
- Provided supervision and guidance; Mediator
- Active observer during group therapy sessions
- Team building amongst staff
- Completion of daily paperwork and logs
- Transportation
- Meals
- Management of clients daily living skills

Self-Employed – Seattle, WA

Professional Nanny

January 2008 - June 2009

- Provided full-time care for one girl, age four months
- Management of daily living necessities
- Transportation
- House management
- Engaged in, and taught age-appropriate learning activities

Self-Employed - Blackhawk, CA

Professional Nanny

April 2006 - August 2007

- Provided full-time care for one girl, age four months
- Management of daily living necessities
- · House management
- Engaged in, and taught age-appropriate learning activities

OfficeTeam - Walnut Creek, CA

Office Administrator

February 2005 - January 2006

- Customer Service
- Answering telephones
- Daily use of Microsoft Word, Excel, and Quickbooks
- Account management

Integrity Home Loan Group – Concord, CA

Mortgage Consultant/Account Executive

April 2004 - February 2005

- Consistency in closing numerous loans
- Customer service in sales
- Trained and mentored new hires
- Assisted with open houses
- Administrative duties
- Management and advertising
- · Lead follow-up and closing

QFI Financial Inc. - Pleasant Hill, CA

Mortgage Consultant/Account Executive

January 2003 - April 2004

- Consistency in closing numerous loans
- Customer service in sales
- Trained and mentored new hires
- Assisted with open houses
- Daily cold calling
- · Management and advertising
- Lead follow-up and closing

Vector Marketing – Napa, CA

Field Sales Leader/Account Executive

March 2003 - December 2003

- Consistently ranked amongst the top three in sales and customer service
- Motivating and mentoring sales representatives
- Weekly phone sessions and daily cold-calling
- Field training co-workers and other offices
- Sales lead follow-up and closing
- Management and advertising

Volunteer Experience

First 5 California

Early Childhood Educator (2012)

This was an Ethnographic placement position while attending JFKU, giving me the opportunity to teach classes and work with the staff and families face-to-face within the local community on various levels.

Glide

Volunteer (2004)

I played an integral part in aiding the homeless with proper food and the preparation for their meals.

Best Buddies California

Volunteer (2002 – 2003)

Engaged in mentoring, teaching and assisting mentally and physically disabled individuals on a weekly basis.

Skills

Leadership, Statistical Data Analysis, Marketing/Advertising, Consulting, Research, Sales, Clinical Report Writing, Client Relationship Management, Project Management Scheduling, Risk Assessment, Microsoft Office, Interviewing, Public Speaking, Supervisory, Community Outreach, Employee Training, Cross-team Collaboration, Attention to Detail, Communication (written, oral, interpersonal), Cultural Awareness, Diversity and Inclusion, Career and Competency Assessment.